#### **RAIHAN SHARIF**

**IMPORT MANAGER** 

(Till 30th January 2020)

PADMA GROUP,

Office no-07, Level-09, Rupayan Trade Centre,

Bangla Motor, Dhaka-1000 Bangladesh

Mobile: +8801741-138607

E-Mail: sharifraihan75@gmail.com



# **CAREER SUMMARY**

Worked as one of the key members of PADMA GROUP Company. As an import manager, during my tenure my major correspondences were with big foreign suppliers like Emirate National Oil Company (ENOC UAE), Pennsylvania Petroleum International (PPI USA), R.L Steels & Energy Ltd(INDIA) for placing order, negotiating prices, document related work etc. In every year, I managed order over Imillion liter lubricants, 30k KG Greases were imported from ENOC (UAE) & at least 10 shipments from PPI (USA). Over 500 MT Flat Bar was imported from R.L Steels (INDIA). I have look after All procedures of import activities of these items. More than 60 LC's I have handled in each year during my tenure. Beyond procurement, I have to look over the monthly sales status and send report to clients. Analyzing the sales flow and took measures according to the findings.

## **CAREER (WITHIN GROUP)**

Import Manager - January 2014 – 2020 January

Assistant Manager (Import & Commercial) - January 2011 – 2013 Executive Officer (Import & Commercial) - October 2009-2010

### **JOB DIMENSIONS:**

- To perform all the Import related correspondence with the foreign suppliers.
- To perform all the correspondence with the bank regarding L/C
- To perform LC costing, duty calculation, Landing cost of each shipment
- Monitor the Lubricating oil sales in every month
- Prepared monthly sales report & submit to top management as required.
- Prepared marketing activities report in each quarter & send it to foreign suppliers
- Placing order to foreign suppliers in in proper time to avoid product shortage.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Business Administration	2005	
East West University, Dhaka, Bangladesh; CGPA: 3.62 (Scale of 4)		
Bachelor of Commerce (Pass)	1995	

Dhaka City College, Result 2<sup>nd</sup> Class

## **IT QUALIFICAITON**

International Diploma in Computer studies

NCC, I.B.C.S -PRIMAX, Dhanmondi Dhaka, Division: Credit (68.9%)

#### **EXPOSURE VISIT:**

Participation of Lubricants Training & CRM Module, Dubai, 17-19 September, 2017

## **PROFESSIONAL TRAINING**

Completed a Training Course from Rahman Mostafa Alam & Co. (Chartered Accountant Firm) as an Audit Assistant, from June 2008 to January 09.

Tave good confinitumcation sk	$\mathbf{O}$	Have	good	communication	skil
-------------------------------	--------------	------	------	---------------	------

- O Excellent analytical skills and expert with numbers and figures
- O To work while under pressure
- O Accept and fulfill all responsibilities given to me
- O Computer and technological skills

## **BIOGRAPHY:**

Father's Name : Late Waseque Uddin Ahmed

Mother's Name : Shahana Ahmed Date of Birth : 18<sup>th</sup> March 1975

Permanent Address : Dist.-Comilla, Vill.- Shindhuria para

Thana- Burichang, Cantonment

### **REFERENCES:**

Md. Mustafizur Rahman FCASaifuddin AhmedManaging PartnerTax Adviser & Head of AccountsRAHMAN MOSTAFA ALAM & COASIA INDUSTRIES (PVT) LTD

Chartered Accountants (Subsidiary organization of Padma Group)
Paramount Heights (7th Floor-D2) Office no-07, Level-09, Rupayan Trade Centre,

65/2/1, Box Culvert Road
Purana Paltan, Dhaka-1000
Ph: 9553449(Off). 01819-2253449

Bangla Motor, Dhaka-1000 Bangladesh
Ph:9337552(ext-104). 01915623940

**CERTIFICATION:** I, the undersigned, certify that, to the best of my Knowledge and belief, this CV correctly describes me, my qualifications and my experience. I understand that any willful misstatement described herein may lead to disqualification or dismissal, if employed.

Rain Bain

**RAIHAN SHARIF**